KIRK VICKERS: The next exercise, the next core exercise that we're going to do is called the single-leg butterfly.
We're going to go back into our 90-90 position.
You'll notice that we do a lot of movement out of this 90-90 position, a very important position to develop and bring in those small deep muscles within the body.
What we're going to do now, keep the low back flat and we're going to go into a butterfly position.
Letting that leg open up, we're going to call in some of the deep inner thigh muscles as well as trying to keep that low back flat.
The key here is don't make the movement easy.
Try to keep that low back flat.
That's going to put you into a lot more tension and a lot more stress through the area that we're trying to work but that's what we're trying to develop, even if you only do a few.
We'll go one leg and then the other leg; each time, forcing our low back down, belly button to spine, low back flat.
Toes are up, take it as wide we can, get some stretch through the inner thigh so we're working several things with one movement and one exercise.
Come back, watch.
I feel my back arching; I force it back down, come back up.